# Andrei Chasovskikh

Telephone: +436643630284

E-mail: <a href="mailto:andrey.chasovskikh@gmail.com">andrey.chasovskikh@gmail.com</a>

Website: <a href="http://andreycha.info">http://andreycha.info</a>
Location: Vienna, Austria

#### **Profile**

Technical lead with more than 10 years of experience designing and developing distributed, highly available systems and multitier enterprise applications. My experience includes development of betting and financial software, ETL solutions, and medical information systems. I always strive to make things better: be it codebase or development process. Big enthusiast of DevOps values. Have spoken at several IT conferences.

#### Recent experience

#### bwin.party (part of Entain Group), Vienna, Austria. May 2016 - present

Position: technical lead (February 2019 – present)

Leading an international team of up to 6 people (up to 5 software engineers and 1 QA engineer). Team is responsible for several mission critical services (24/7 with up to 3000 RPS) providing bet content translations, master data, and scoreboard updates, with a focus on a brand new trading platform:

- migrated one of the core services from relational to graph database without downtime, the transition opened up opportunities to easily build new features
- designed several improvements in translations service decreased operational costs and improved performance comparing to previous version of the platform
- increased stability of releases and overall quality of deliveries by introducing continuous testing
- decreased lead time for releases from several days to 1 day by making services always to be ready for release and significantly decreasing manual steps during release preparation using CI/CD pipeline
- · successfully onboarded and developed the team consisting completely of new hires
- created a set of onboarding documentation which decreased onboarding time for new members

Position: senior software engineer (May 2016 – January 2019)

Worked in a team responsible for several services distributing bet content from trading department to frontend department:

- replaced several different components which accessed shared bet content database directly and had large memory footprint with centralized subscription-based channel based on Kafka updates and Redis Pubsub
- introduced usage of feature branches, merge requests and code reviews after migration from SVN to Git and GitLab: it improved team involvement and knowledge sharing, helped to find issues earlier
- initiated and drove converting most of automated E2E tests to service tests: builds became stable, team gained confidence in product quality and started to spend less time on testing and stabilizing releases

Keywords: C#, .NET Framework, .NET Core, Docker, Apache Kafka, GraphQL, Elasticsearch, Kibana, MS Visual Studio, Redis, MS SQL Server, Cassandra, Neo4j, Swagger, IIS, git, SVN, GitLab, Jenkins, GitLab CI, VersionOne, NUnit, Moq, TDD, Kanban, Scrum, event-driven architecture, microservices

# Broadridge Financial Solutions (Paladyne Systems before September 2011), St. Petersburg, Russia. March 2011 – April 2016

Position: senior software developer (September 2015 – April 2016)

Helped Price Master team:

- investigated and fixed several major performance issues, both backend and UI (WPF)
- streamlined build and deployment processes using TeamCity and Octopus Deploy, that helped to understand which versions are deployed on which environments

Position: software developer (April 2011 – August 2015)

Worked on a greenfield product for reference data quality and arbitration:

- integrated with Security Master product: loading and keeping up to date 10+ million entities
- developed multiple input and output adapters for data transformation engine, made a lot of improvements based on a real usage
- implemented apply/diff algorithm for document storage

Worked on Security Master, a product for managing securities reference data, and ETL Manager, a product for loading reference data from vendors into Security Master:

- designed and developed 'Custom Dictionaries' feature
- designed and developed 'Custom Calculated Fields' feature
- helped to keep a client by developing custom FormPF solution
- took part in developing 'Auto-Failover' feature
- · investigated and solved client issues
- was replacing sole developer of ETL Manager, after that onboarded and mentored two new developers for 6 months

Keywords: C#, .NET Framework, Java, PowerShell, Infragistics, DevExpress, MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, MS SQL Server, IIS, Tomcat, TFS, git, Jira,BitBucket, Bamboo, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, TDD, MS Test, xUnit, JUnit, Rhino Mocks, Moq, NSubstitute, Mockito, Scrum, Kanban

#### Brain Systems, St. Petersburg, Russia. September 2010 - March 2011

Position: software developer

- Helped to win a client by developing an e-archive system prototype: full application design and development
- Took part in developing Java web application for medical municipal institution, both front-end and back-end parts

Keywords: C#, .NET Framework, Silverlight, Entity Framework, WCF RIA Services, MS SQL Server, Java, Smart GWT, Oracle, Jasper Reports, JBoss, NetBeans, SVN, Redmine

#### Kostasoft, St. Petersburg, Russia. September 2008 - September 2010

Position: junior software developer/software developer

Took part in developing medical information system, Avicenna.NET. This included writing new functionality (from UI to backend code), solving client issues, and writing technical documentation.

- made planning, development, and feature delivery more predictable by introducing weekly sprints and planning sessions
- improved knowledge sharing in the team by suggesting and leading weekly retrospective meetings

Keywords: C#, .NET Framework, DevExpress, MS Visual Studio, MS SQL Server, SVN, Gemini

## **Academic experience**

#### St. Petersburg Polytechnical University. February 2010 - February 2014

Have lead exercises and several lectures for "Databases" course (MS SQL Server, T-SQL, NoSQL) every spring semester.

#### **Education**

#### 2004 – 2010, St. Petersburg Polytechnical University

Master equivalent degree in Software Engineering. GPA: 4.5/5.0.

### **Talks & publications**

- "async/await: avoiding common mistakes", DotNext, December 2014
- "Windows Phone applications security", HackInParis, June 2013
- "Inspection of Windows Phone applications", Black Hat Abu Dhabi, December 2012
- "Clustering algorithms overview", <a href="http://web-analitik.info/">http://web-analitik.info/</a>, September 2010